Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development Records UA009
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development Records
1879 -- 2015
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Eliot-Pearson Children's School
Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development
UA009
32.8 Linear Feet 43 boxes and 1 oversize folder
122 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into eleven series: Women's Education Association; Ruggles St. Nursery School and Nursery Training School of Boston; Board of Managers, Trustees, and Corporation records; Financial records; Annual and self-study report; Faculty meeting minutes and reports; Course materials; 2017 accessions; Office files; Audiovisual materials; and Student teacher files.
Biographical / Historical
In 1996, the Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Studies became the Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development. The department, already prominent in its field, grew between this date and the early 2010s in number of faculty members and lecturers, in courses offered, and in programs that serve students, researchers and families in the greater Boston area.
One landmark event that occurred during the period soon after the department's name change was the endowment of the Bergstrom Family Chair in Applied Developmental Science in 1997, which was described by Sol Gittleman in An Entrepreneurial University: The Transformation of Tufts 1976-2002 as "the nation's first professorship explicitly framed in ADS terms."
The department's facilities include the Eliot-Pearson Children's School, the Tufts Educational Day Care Center, and the Evelyn G. Pitcher Curriculum Lab. Students complement their course work with activities that take place in these facilities and, according to the course catalog for the academic year 2010-2011, with field work with children in a "wide range of applied settings, including schools, hospitals, clinics, day care centers, educational television studios, museums, and juvenile courts."
Undergraduates can choose either a major or a minor in Child Development. There are three Masters programs and a doctoral program in Applied Child Development. The catalog for 2000-2001 described ADS as "an emerging, interdisciplinary field that generates and uses theory and research about human development to improve the lives of children, youth, and families around the world." Students can follow a number of tracks throughout their education in Child Development, the three most common being preparation for a career in behavioral science, a career in human services, and a career in education. For those seeking the latter, the department offers a pre-K to 3 teacher certification program, and an elementary school teacher program in cooperation with the Department of Education. Another joint program is the M.A. in child and family policy, offered with the Department of Urban and Environmental Policy.
As of 2011, the department runs a number of research centers, institutes and special programs, including:Center for Applied Child Development Center for Reading and Language Research Child and Family WebGuide Developmental Technologies Research Group Healthy Families Evaluation Program Home-School Connection Program Institute for Applied Research in Youth Development. The International Adoption Project Tufts Adoption and Development Project
Information about these programs can be found on the department's website.
Every two years since 2001, the department, in partnership with the Communication and Media Studies Program, has presented the Eliot-Pearson Award for Excellence in Children's Media. These awards are nicknamed The Abbys, in honor of educator and co-founder Abigail Adams Eliot.
The Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development's mission is "to contribute to a more just, caring and inclusive society."
Custodial History
All material accessioned prior to 1997 was originally arranged by subject, and no attempt was made to recreate original order. Material relating to administering the collection was removed to the documentation files of the collection in the archives.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of administrative material including annual reports, correspondence, meeting minutes of the Board of Managers and the faculty, financial reports, and office files which document the development of the school from its association with the Women's Education Association, through its self-governance, to its eventual merger with Tufts University. Also included in the collection are Child Development student records; syllabi and course listings; audiovisual materials including photographs, slides, lantern slides, and videocassettes; licensure material for the department; and historic material about and kept by the department, including scrapbooks. The primary focus of this collection is the administrative records.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, 2008-2017.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Departments and Programs; Curriculum and Instruction -- Teaching Material
- Women's Education Association, 1917 -- 1929; UA009.001; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of materials relating to the Women's Education Association, out of which grew the Ruggles St. Nursery School and later, Eliot-Pearson.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Annual reports, 1917 -- 1922; UA009.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Annual reports, 1923 -- 1929; UA009.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1921 -- 1924; UA009.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Nursery School Committee, minutes, 1924 -- 1927; UA009.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
- Ruggles St. Nursery School and Nursery Training School of Boston, records, 1879 -- 1972; 1920 -- 1959; UA009.002; 0.75 Linear Feet
  This series contains reports, articles, minutes, brochures, correspondence, and financial records associated with the Ruggles Street Nursery Training School, which became the Nursery Training School of Boston in 1926.
  - Annual reports, 1942 -- 1955; UA009.002.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Articles by staff, 1923 -- 1925; UA009.002.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1924 -- 1948; UA009.002.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1955 -- 1957; UA009.002.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Brochures, 1922 -- 1970; UA009.002.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Community Health Association, 1939 -- 1942; UA009.002.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Corporation meeting minutes, 1902 -- 1945; UA009.002.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Corporation records, 1927 -- 1931; UA009.002.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1922 -- 1925; UA009.002.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1926 -- 1927; UA009.002.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1936; UA009.002.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Curriculum, 1923 -- 1955; UA009.002.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Deeds and mortgages, 1879 -- 1959; UA009.002.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Nursery Training School News, 1954; UA009.002.002.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2)
  - Early relations, other schools, 1922 -- 1928; UA009.002.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Finances, 1922 -- 1952; UA009.002.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Financial Aid, 1944 -- 1951; UA009.002.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Self-study, 1922 -- 1972; UA009.002.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Transfer of property to Nursery Training School, 1951 -- 1952; UA009.002.003.00005 (Box 3)
- Board of Managers, Trustees and Corporation records, 1927 -- 1964; 1927 -- 1962; UA009.003; 1.0 Linear Feet
  - Board of managers and corporation records, 1955 -- 1962; UA009.003.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Board of managers, minutes, 1927 -- 1930; UA009.003.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Board of managers, minutes, 1930 -- 1932; UA009.003.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Board of managers, minutes, 1932 -- 1934; UA009.003.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Board of managers, minutes, 1936 -- 1943; UA009.003.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Board of managers, minutes, 1944 -- 1949; UA009.003.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Board of managers, minutes, 1950 -- 1954; UA009.003.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Board of managers, minutes, 1955 -- 1962; UA009.003.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Board of trustees, membership lists and correspondence, 1962 -- 1964; UA009.003.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Board of trustees, minutes, 1962 -- 1964; UA009.003.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Corporation, fundraising, 1962; UA009.003.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Corporation lists, 1927 -- 1955; UA009.003.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Corporation records, 1927 -- 1939; UA009.003.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Corporation records, 1937 -- 1949; UA009.003.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Corporation records, 1950 -- 1954; UA009.003.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - Corporation records, 1955 -- 1962; UA009.003.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - Finance committee, minutes and correspondence, 1963; UA009.003.005.00010 (Box 5)
- Financial records, 1935 -- 1964; UA009.004; 0.25 Linear Feet
  This series consists of financial records of the Eliot Pearson School.
  - Finance reports, 1939 -- 1955; UA009.004.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Finance reports, 1955 -- 1964; UA009.004.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Internal Revenue Service, 1935 -- 1957; UA009.004.006.00003 (Box 6)
- Annual and self-study report, 1940 -- 1991; 1975 -- 1991; UA009.005; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains annual reports from the director and members of the Advisory Board as well as a self-study report. The directors reports range from 1940-1962 and the Board member reports range from 1971-1991. Of particular interest is the Institutional Self-Study report which provides a cohesive picture of how the Eliot-Pearson Department meets the demands of its students and the field. Folders are arranged alphabetically.
  - Annual report, 1972 -- 1973; UA009.005.007.00001 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1973 -- 1974; UA009.005.007.00002 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1976 -- 1977; UA009.005.007.00003 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1977 -- 1978; UA009.005.007.00004 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1978 -- 1979; UA009.005.007.00005 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1979 -- 1980; UA009.005.007.00006 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1980 -- 1981; UA009.005.007.00007 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1982 -- 1983; UA009.005.007.00008 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1984 -- 1985; UA009.005.007.00009 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1986 -- 1987; UA009.005.007.00010 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1987 -- 1988; UA009.005.007.00011 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1988 -- 1989; UA009.005.007.00012 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1989 -- 1990; UA009.005.007.00013 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1990 -- 1991; UA009.005.007.00014 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Director's annual reports, 1940 -- 1946; UA009.005.007.00015 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Director's report, 1957; UA009.005.007.00016 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Director's annual report, 1959; UA009.005.007.00017 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Director's annual report, 1960; UA009.005.007.00018 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Director's annual report, 1961; UA009.005.007.00019 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Director's annual report, 1962; UA009.005.007.00020 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Institutional self-study report, 1985; UA009.005.007.00021 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
- Faculty meeting minutes and reports, 1956 -- 2002; 1980 -- 1998; UA009.006; 2.4 Linear Feet
  This series contains faculty meeting minutes and reports. The majority of the material ranges from 1985-1997. Folders are arranged alphabetically.
  - Faculty meeting agendas, 1998; UA009.006.007.00022 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meeting materials, 1994; UA009.006.007.00023 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meeting minutes (to be filed), 1998 -- 2002; UA009.006.007.00024 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1956 -- 1959; UA009.006.007.00025 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1959 -- 1962; UA009.006.007.00026 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1984 -- 1985; UA009.006.007.00027 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meetings, 1985 -- 1986; UA009.006.007.00028 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meetings, 1986 -- 1987; UA009.006.007.00029 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meetings, 1987 -- 1988; UA009.006.007.00030 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meetings, 1988 -- 1989; UA009.006.007.00031 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meetings, 1989 -- 1990; UA009.006.007.00032 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meetings, 1990 -- 1991; UA009.006.007.00033 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meetings, 1991 -- 1992; UA009.006.007.00034 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meetings, 1992 -- 1993; UA009.006.007.00035 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty minutes, 1993 -- 1994; UA009.006.007.00036 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty minutes, 1996 -- 1997; UA009.006.007.00037 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 1998 -- 1999; UA009.006.007.00038 (Box UA009 Shared 1)
  - Faculty retreat minutes, 1987 -- 1992; UA009.006.008.00001 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Full faculty meetings-minutes, 1994; UA009.006.008.00002 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Full faculty minutes, 1996; UA009.006.008.00003 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Full faculty meetings, 1997 -- 1998; UA009.006.008.00004 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Senior faculty mtgs., 1983 -- 1990; UA009.006.008.00005 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Senior faculty mtgs., 1990 -- 1991; UA009.006.008.00006 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Senior fac. minutes, 1993 -- 1994; UA009.006.008.00007 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Sr. fac., 1994 -- 1995; UA009.006.008.00008 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Senior faculty meetings-minutes, 1995; UA009.006.008.00009 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Senior faculty meeting minutes, 1996; UA009.006.008.00010 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Registration section status summary, 1990; UA009.006.008.00011 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Reports from committees, 1989; UA009.006.008.00012 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Tenured faculty meetings, 1997 -- 1998; UA009.006.008.00013 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
- Course materials, 1885 -- 1999; 1953 -- 1996; UA009.007; 3.65 Linear Feet
  This series contains brochures and catalogs from all periods in the history of the Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development. These publications demonstrate the wide range of courses offered over the different incarnations of the Department. Also included are course outlines from 1943-1968 and syllabi from 1983-1996 which demonstrate the type of information being offered in the classroom during these different phases. Folders are arranged alphabetically.
  - Brochures, 1926 -- 1945; UA009.007.008.00014 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Brochures, 1945 -- 1959; UA009.007.008.00015 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Brochures, 1960 -- 1978; UA009.007.008.00016 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Brochures, 1979 -- 1989; UA009.007.008.00017 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Catalogues, 1938 -- 1950; UA009.007.008.00018 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Catalogues, 1950 -- 1965; UA009.007.008.00019 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Catalogs (undergraduate), 1984 -- 1989; UA009.007.008.00020 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Catalogs (graduate), 1993 -- 1999; UA009.007.008.00021 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Commentaries by Emelyn D. Osgood on Froebel's Mother Plays, 1885; UA009.007.008.00022 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Committee on child study major, 1963 -- 1966; UA009.007.008.00023 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Course outlines, bibliographies, 1943 -- 1955; UA009.007.008.00024 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Course outlines, bibliographies, 1956 -- 1958; UA009.007.008.00025 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Course outlines, bibliographies, 1959 -- 1960; UA009.007.008.00026 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Course outlines, bibliographies, 1960 -- 1961; UA009.007.008.00027 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Course outlines, bibliographies, 1962 -- 1963; UA009.007.008.00028 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Course outlines, bibliographies, 1963; UA009.007.008.00029 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Course outlines, bibliographies, 1964 -- 1968; UA009.007.008.00030 (Box UA009 Shared 2)
  - Course schedules, 1953 -- 1960; UA009.007.009.00001 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Curriculum, 1940 -- 1962; UA009.007.009.00002 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - E- P Times, 1989 -- 1990; UA009.007.009.00003 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Experiments in Free Play, Parts I-IV, L.B. Murphy, L.J. Stone, E. Lerner, E. Beyer, et al., 1941; UA009.007.009.00004 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Great Britain, Great Britain- D, 1938; UA009.007.009.00005 (Box data_value_missing_b5d51cc31fab1607a925c38d0c809869)
  - Special courses and projects, 1934 -- 1963; UA009.007.009.00006 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Special courses and projects, 1941 -- 1957; UA009.007.009.00007 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Student teaching course, 1944 -- 1964; UA009.007.009.00008 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Arthur Anastopoulos, 1994; UA009.007.009.00009 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Terrell Clark, 1996; UA009.007.009.00010 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Anne Daniels, 1996; UA009.007.009.00011 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Margery Davies, 1996; UA009.007.009.00012 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Julie Dobrow, 1996; UA009.007.009.00013 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Ann Easterbrooks, 1996; UA009.007.009.00014 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Sylvia Feinburg, 1995 -- 1996; UA009.007.009.00015 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] David Henry Feldman, 1994 -- 1996; UA009.007.009.00016 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Calvin "Chip" Gidney, 1995 -- 1996; UA009.007.009.00017 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Charles Greenbaum, 1996; UA009.007.009.00018 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Morse Hamilton, 1994; UA009.007.009.00019 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Mathilda Holzman, 1986 -- 1992; UA009.007.009.00020 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Charna Levine, 1983 -- 1994; UA009.007.009.00021 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Debbie LeeKeenan, 1994; UA009.007.009.00022 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Thomas Mela, 1986 -- 1993; UA009.007.009.00023 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Allysa McCabe, 1988 -- 1991; UA009.007.009.00024 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Jayanthi Mistry, 1991 -- 1996; UA009.007.009.00025 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Lynn Meltzer, 1985 -- 1993; UA009.007.009.00026 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Fran Jacobs, 1988 -- 1991; UA009.007.009.00027 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Tammy Mulligan, 1995; UA009.007.009.00028 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Barbara Noga, 1993 -- 1994; UA009.007.009.00029 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Roberta Pasternack, 1992; UA009.007.009.00030 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Peggy Powers, 1994; UA009.007.009.00031 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Anthony Rao, 1994; UA009.007.009.00032 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Marion Reynolds, 1991 -- 1996; UA009.007.009.00033 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Fred Rothbaum, 1983 -- 1995; UA009.007.009.00034 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Dorothy Sang, 1995; UA009.007.009.00035 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] George Scarlett, 1990 -- 1996; UA009.007.009.00036 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Martha Sellers, 1990 -- 1996; UA009.007.009.00037 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Sidney Strauss, 1996; UA009.007.009.00038 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Donald Wertlieb, 1988 -- 1993; UA009.007.009.00039 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Maryanne Wolf, 1991 -- 1994; UA009.007.009.00040 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Uri Wilensky, 1994 -- 1995; UA009.007.009.00041 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - [Syllabi] Janet Zeller, 1995 -- 1996; UA009.007.009.00042 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Great Britain Pre War D, 1938; UA009.007.025.00001 (Box data_value_missing_b5d51cc31fab1607a925c38d0c809869)
  - Curriculum 1962-1964; Graduate Prospectus 1993, 1962 -- 1993; UA009.007.025.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box data_value_missing_b5d51cc31fab1607a925c38d0c809869)
  - Workbooks contributed by Miss Susan Andrews from her work 1907-10 in the Fannie E. Smith Kindergarten Training School, 1907 -- 1910; UA009.007.026.00001 (Box 26)
  - Workbooks contributed by Miss Susan Andrews from her work 1907-10 in the Fannie E. Smith Kindergarten Training School, 1907 -- 1910; UA009.007.027.00001 (Box 27)
- 2017 accessions, circa 1928 -- 2015; UA009.008; 5.43 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, 2017, accession UA-2018-017.
  This series contains syllabi and course listings; licensure material for the department; historic material about and kept by the department, including information about children in wartime; and scrapbooks of newsclippings and photographs about the Nursery Training School, the Ruggles Street Nursery School, and the Eliot Pearson School.
  - Child Development 001-164 course syllabi, circa 1984 -- 2014; UA009.008.035; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 35)
  - Child Development 166-291 course syllabi; department course listings, circa 1984 -- 2015; UA009.008.036; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 36)
  - Licensure material, circa 2001 -- 2012; UA009.008.037; .4 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_0d381823e2d05da878d7d8efc70573e7, Box 37)
    20 years from date of creation.
  - Historic Eliot Pearson material, circa 1931 -- 1992; UA009.008.038; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_7f52bf14552ac00710e9d19648865271, Box 38)
    Includes literature on children and families during wartime and other non-Eliot Pearson publications; information on the Tufts-Eliot Pearson merger; material about the Great Britain and Northern Ireland Nursery School, the World Organization for Early Childhood Education, and other non-Eliot Pearson organizations; as well as miscellaneous forms and correspondence.
  - Nursery Training School, Ruggles Street Nursery School scrapbook and photographs, circa 1930 -- 1995; UA009.008.039; .13 Linear Feet (Box 39)
  - Nursery Training School, Eliot Pearson scrapbooks and photographs, circa 1930 -- 1980; UA009.008.040; .4 Linear Feet (Box 40)
  - Nursery Training School, Eliot Pearson scrapbooks and photgraphs, circa 1928 -- 1980; UA009.008.041; .9 Linear Feet (Box 41)
- Office files, 1902 -- 2000; 1933 -- 1967; UA009.010; 6.65 Linear Feet
  This series contains information which documents the operations of the Ruggles Street Nursery through the present day administration of the Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development. Included in the office files are reports, faculty files, and fundraising information. Included in this series are several folders containing information on Abigail Adams Eliot. These folders include some of her publications as well as her correspondence with members of the faculty both during her time at the school and after her retirement. Additionally there are several sets of correspondence which reflect the administration of the school. Folders are arranged alphabetically in two complete runs.
  - Applied Child Development Center, 1986 -- 1989; UA009.010.009.00043 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Bibliography of faculty publications, 1957; UA009.010.009.00044 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - BIDIP, 1997; UA009.010.009.00045 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - BIDIP, 1998; UA009.010.009.00046 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - BIDIP, 1999; UA009.010.009.00047 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - BIDIP, 2000; UA009.010.009.00048 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - BIDIP info, 1993 -- 1996; UA009.010.009.00049 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Building committee, 1979 -- 1983; UA009.010.009.00050 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Building funds accounts, 1980 -- 1985; UA009.010.009.00051 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Building fund committee, 1980; UA009.010.009.00052 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
    This date is approximate.
  - Chairman's correspondence, A-B, 1989; UA009.010.009.00053 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Chairman's correspondence, C, 1989; UA009.010.009.00054 (Box UA009 Shared 3)